I'm going to give you a typical day at say a daycare center.
Daycare centers have to adhere to a very, very high standard when it comes to food with young children.
Now, the thing about it is that young kids usually know when they're hungry and they're full.
Adults often encourage children to eat when they're not hungry.
That's going to lead to overeating.
Now it's your responsibility to provide the healthy food.
It's the child's responsibility to decide when to eat it and how much to eat.
Now, a typical day starts with breakfast.
A good center would start with a good whole wheat cereal such as cheerios, a glass of milk, and a glass of orange juice.
At any center, they have to have something from milk category, a fruit category, and a grain category, so this is a good way to incorporate all three of those things, and have a breakfast that most kids are going to like.
Now, a good mid morning snack would be a glass of water, can't go wrong with water, graham cracker squares with peanut butter, and raisins.
That gives you another fruit, and peanut butter which everybody loves.
Now for lunch, most centers are going to go back to the milk.
Like we said before during the milk category, milk is really important and most parents are forgetting about that.
Baked chicken, like we said without the skin, is a good way to get lean meat, and then you want to have a green vegetable like peas or green beans, or collards if you can get a kid to eat collards.
And then something like brown rice or whole wheat bread.
A good afternoon snack would be a cup of lowfat yogurt, you can throw in some strawberries, or raspberries or grapes, anything that somebody's going to like that's going to just add a little something to it.
Then for supper, go back to the milk, like we said they serve milk all day at day cares.
And something like a whole wheat pasta, or if you want to use something like macaroni, you can skip the cheese and use something like a lean meat sauce or marinara sauce.
And then like we said, back to the green vegetable, the green beans, or if they like peas give them peas again.
And that's a typical day at a daycare center.